Register of the Zhongguo Guo Min Dang Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Zhongguo guo min dang records
1894-1987
2006C29
Hoover Institution Archives
1988 microfilm reels (262.0 linear feet)
Relates to political conditions in and government of China and Taiwan.
Zhongguo guo min dang.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
The microfilm was acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives from 2003 to 2010.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Archival Materials note
Chiang Kai-shek diaries, Hoover Institution Archives
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Records of the Central Reform Committee (series numbers 6.41, 6.42, and 6.43) are digitized and may also be viewed on a workstation in the Archives reading room.
Location of Originals
Originals at Kuomintang archives, Taipei, Taiwan.
Historical Note
Sun Yat-sen and other overseas Chinese concerned about the situation in China founded the Hsing Chung Hui in Hawaii on 24 November 1894. This organization was superseded by the Tung Meng Hui, formed by Sun and other Chinese in Tokyo on 20 August 1905. The headquarters of the Tung Meng Hui moved to Nanjing after the Republic of China was established in January 1912. Later that year it merged with other groups to form the Kuomintang (Zhongguo guo min dang or Nationalist Party of the Republic of China), with Sun as chairman.
The organization of the Kuomintang (KMT) expanded rapidly. At the First National Party Congress in January 1924 a party constitution was adopted. The congress elected a Central Executive Committee (CEC) to handle party affairs when the congress was not in session, and established a Central Control Committee to oversee party affairs. The CEC was headed by the director of the party, who had final decision-making power over the resolutions passed by the CEC. Sun Yat-sen, who died on 12 March 1925, was the first director. He set up a Political Committee in 1924 to handle party-government relations. At first the Political Committee met by itself, but in 1927 it began meeting with the CEC. The CEC elected a Standing Committee to handle party affairs when the full CEC was not in session. Various departments were established under the CEC, with departmental reorganizations occurring occasionally. This structure remained largely unchanged until 1950.
In 1938, after the war with Japan began, a National Supreme Defense Commission was founded with KMT director general Chiang Kai-shek as its head. All CEC departments, the entire national government, and all military affairs fell under the jurisdiction of this new unit.
The Kuomintang (KMT) was defeated in 1949 by Chinese Communist Party forces and forced to relocate in Taiwan. Following the removal, the KMT entered a period of reorientation and reformation. A Central Reform Committee (CRC) was established in August 1949 to determine the most effective way to revitalize the party. It drafted a new party platform and studied organizational changes, among other activities.
The recommendations of the CRC were subsequently adopted by the Seventh National Party Congress (October 10-20, 1952), and the former Central Executive Committee and the Central Control Committee were replaced by a single Central Committee (CC). The CC elected a Central Standing Committee (CSC), chaired by the director general, with a secretary general to oversee the work of the party departments and committees. Initially the CSC had six sections concerning party affairs in Taiwan, party affairs in mainland China, party affairs overseas, propaganda, handling social organizations, and social and economic research and planning strategies against the enemy. The CSC also had four committees for evaluation, discipline, finance, and party history. A Secretariat for the CSC handled documents, accounting, personnel, and party member welfare.
Another part of the KMT's self-reformation movement in the early 1950s involved intensification of training and indoctrination of cadres working with various mass organizations, like the Chinese Federal of Labor, Chinese Women's Anti-Aggression League, and National Association of Youth Organizations, formed. A system of "basic party cadres" was established to revitalize the party and ensure thorough implementation of party policies and programs at the local level. The cadres worked closely with youth, farmers, laborers, and other groups.
For the two decades after the 1952 reform, the KMT presided over an increasingly repressive political system, followed in the 1970s by cycles of loosening and tightening of controls. Facilitated by party members in critical government positions at all levels, the KMT was able to activate its policies through the legislative and executive yuan (branches) of the government.
The basic structure of the party remained fairly constant during this period. Its organization formed a pyramid paralleling the organization of the government. Local units of up to 15 members formed the base, with the subdistrict, district, county, and provincial organizations above it. At the top was the central unit, the Central Committee. Each level of organization maintained a central committee and an advisory committee. The committees at the base were elected directly by party members, and the congresses (known as assemblies at district and lower levels) at each higher level elected the central and advisory committees for their respective levels.
Going down the pyramid, the Provincial Congress met every two years. It decided on the methods for implementing the KMT's programs and elected the Central Committee. The County Congress met annually to elect its committee members and to formulate policy at its level of authority. The district and subdistrict assemblies were comprised of all party members in the area concerned. The basic unit of 3 to 15 members was responsible for carrying the party's message to the people and recruiting members. Members with no fixed residence, such as railroad workers, seamen, other vocational groups, and Overseas Chinese, had special organizations under the direct control of the central party headquarters.
At the national level, the National Congress, scheduled to meet every few years, continued to be the highest unit of the party. Its chief duties were to amend the party constitution, determine the party platform and policies, review the work of the Central Committee, train and guide party cadres, elect the president, and elect members of the Central Committee.
The Central Committee met annually. Its functions were to execute resolutions of the National Congress and represent the party in its external relations, discuss and administer party and political affairs, organize and direct party branches at various levels, train and guide party cadres, enforce party discipline, and raise funds and administer the party budget.
Because of the large membership of the Central Committee (CC), the real power was vested in its Central Standing Committee (CSC), whose members were elected by the CC. The CSC functioned during the recess of the plenary session of the CC. It could issue orders, make appointments, and call an extraordinary plenary session of the CC when necessary. The CSC initially held unlimited authority because the director general of the party was its chairman, and the ultimate source of power in the party resided with the director general. The director general was elected by the National Congress and possessed absolute veto authority over the decisions of the CC. Chiang Kai-shek was director general from 1938 until his death on 5 April 1975. After his death the position was retired, and Chiang Ching-kuo became party chairman.
A Central Advisory Committee was added in 1969, and the number of seats in the CSC was gradually increased to 21 members.
Scope and Content of Collection
Some of the microfilmed collections of the KMT listed below are described in PDF indexes (traditional Chinese language only) attached below. Please contact the Archives for more information. When visiting the Archives reading room to view the microfilm, please be ready to provide (1) the particular collection identifier, for example 5.1, Hankou, or TE 2, and (2) the microfilm reel numbers.
Since 2003 the Hoover Institution has been working with the KMT to preserve the historical records held in the party's archives in Taipei. The official party records are microfilmed in Taipei, with a use copy of the microfilm deposited at the Hoover Institution.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into groups of records created by subunits of the KMT, such as the Central Reform Committee and Seventh Central Standing Committee, or papers of prominent officials, such as the archive of Wu Zhihui.
China--Politics and government--1912-1949.; Taiwan--Politics and government--1945-1975.
- Records of the National Defense Supreme Commission
  Historical Note
  In 1938, after the war with Japan began, a National Supreme Defense Commission was founded with KMT director general Chiang Kai-shek as its head. All Central Executive Committee departments, the entire national government, and all military affairs fell under the jurisdiction of this new unit.
  - National Defense Supreme Commission Archive (001), 1939-1947 (Reels 1-33)
    Other Finding Aids note
    國防最高委員會檔案: 第一門
  - National Defense Supreme Commission Archive (002), 1939-1947 (Reels 1-8)
    國防最高委員會檔案: 第二門
  - National Defense Supreme Commission Archive (003), 1939-1947 (Reels 1-156, 156A, 157-325)
    國防最高委員會檔案: 第三門
  - National Defense Supreme Commission Archive (004), 1939-1947 (Reels 1-9)
    國防最高委員會檔案: 第四門
  - National Defense Supreme Commission Archive (005), 1939-1947 (Reels 1-4)
    國防最高委員會檔案: 第五門
  - National Defense Supreme Commission Archive (009), 1939-1947 (Reels 1-2)
    國防最高委員會檔案: 第九門
- Records of the Fifth National Party Congress (5.1), 1935 (Reels 1-18)
  Held November 12-23, 1935, in Nanjing, the Fifth National Congress adopted such resolutions as "Enforcement of Local Self-government to Complete the Political Tutelage" and "Consolidation of the National Defense during the National Emergency." It issued a manifesto dealing with psychological, social and political aspects of national reconstruction.
  第五次全國代表大會記錄
- Records of the Fifth Central Executive Committee (5.2), 1935-1944 (Reels 1-73)
  Three plenary sessions of the Fifth Central Executive Committee were held in Nanjing, on 2 December 1935, 10 July 1936, and 14 May 14 1937. The committee was officially terminated in May 1945.
  第五屆中央執行委員會全體會議紀錄
- Records of the Fifth Central Standing Committee (5.3), 1935-1945 (Reels 1-12)
  The committee began functioning in December 1935 and was officially terminated in May 1945.
  五屆中常會第三次會議紀錄
- Records of the Fifth Central Affairs Working Committee (5.4), 1938-1940 (Reels 1-5)
  第五屆中央黨務工作會議紀錄
- Records of the Sixth National Party Congress (6.1), 1945 (Reels 1-17)
  Held May 5-21, 1945, in Chongqing, the Sixth National Congress made public a new platform on May 18 and a new manifesto on May 21. The new platform called for preparations for the promulgation of constitutional government.
  第六全國代表大會會議紀錄
- Records of the Sixth Central Executive Committee (6.2), 1945-1947 (Reels 1-27)
  Four plenary sessions of the Sixth Central Executive Committee were held on 28 May 1945, 1 March 1946, 15 March 1947, 9 September 1947. The first two were held in Chongqing, and the second two in Nanjing. An extraordinary plenary session of the Central Executive Committee was held on 4 April 1948 in Nanjing. The committee was terminated in August 1950.
  第六屆中央執行委員會全體會議記錄
- Records of the Sixth Central Standing Committee (6.3), 1945-1950 (Reels 1-10)
  The committee functioned from May 1945 to August 1950.
  第六屆中央常務委員會會議記錄
- Records of the Central Reform Committee (CRC)
  The KMT formally established the CRC on August 5, 1950, to explore ways to revitalize the party. The CRC, with 16 members, replaced the former Central Executive Committee and the Central Supervisory Committee, which had 50 and 223 members, respectively and became the party's main executive and policy planner body. It had four subcommittees in the areas of cadre training, discipline, finance, and party history. Seven functional sections handled party affairs in Taiwan and mainland China; industrial, professional, youth, and other special party branches; overseas party affairs; propaganda; political activities for KMT members of the government and liaison with friendly parties; collection of information on society and economy and planning of strategies to deal with the enemy; and party-run enterprises and the economic well-being of party members.
  During its two years of existence regular party organs were suspended and their activities were transferred to the CRC. Among other activities, the CRC and its successor drafted a new party platform, studied organizational changes, issued a directive on recruiting new members, and published procedures for cadres working with various mass organizations. It also published Gaizao [ Reform], the official organ of the KMT from 1950 to 1952. The committee's recommendations were adopted by the Seventh National Party Congress in October 1952.
  - Central Reform Committee Archive (6.41), 1949-1954 (Reels 1-13)
    General note
    Digital use copies available in reading room
    中央改造委員會檔案
  - Minutes of the Central Reform Committee Meetings (6.42), 1950-1952 (Reels 1-12)
    中央改造委員會會議紀錄
  - Briefings of the Various Projects of the Central Reform Committee (6.43), 1950-1952 (Reels 1-6)
    中央改造委員會各種工作簡報
- Records of the Seventh National Party Congress (7.1), 1952 (Reels 1-3)
  Held October 10-20, 1952, in Taipei, this was the KMT's first national congress in Taiwan. It adopted the Central Reform Committee's recommendations and created the Central Committee, electing 32 members to it. This committee replaced the Central Executive Committee and the Central Control Committee. The Seventh National Party Congress set the course of the party by revising the General Regulations of the party, forming the basic doctrine to be pursued during the period of the anti-Communist campaign against the mainland, and drafting a detailed party platform to serve as a guide for the working program of party members. It issued a manifesto and platform on October 20, which were the first major statements of party policy on Taiwan. A land reform program was one of its most significant programs.
  第七屆全國代表會會議紀錄
- Records of the Seventh Central Committee (7.2), 1953-1954 (Reels 1-3)
  Eight plenary sessions of the Seventh Central Committee were held in Taipei on 23 October 1952, 5 May 1953, 12 November 1953, 2 August 1954, 1 March 1955, 3 October 1955, 5 May 1956, and 4 March 1957. An extraordinary plenary session was held on 15 February 1954. The committee operated until October 1957.
  第七屆中央執行委員會全體會議記錄
- Records of the Seventh Central Standing Committee (7.3.), 1952-1957 (Reels 1-13)
  The committee functioned from October 1952 to October 1957.
  第七屆中央常務委員會議記錄
- Records of the Seventh National Working Committee (7.4), 1952-1957 (Reels 1-17)
  第七屆中央委員會工作會議紀錄
- Hankou Archive (Hankou), 1924-1927 (Reels 1-28, 28A, 29-167)
  漢口檔案
- Shanghai Huanlong Road Archive (Huan), 1914-1925 (Reels 1-95)
  上海環龍路檔案
- New Life Movement Archive (New Life), 1935-1945 (Reels 1-6)
  In 1934, Chiang Kai-shek and his wife, Soong Meiling, heralded the New Life Movement that would revitalize the Chinese national spirit. Influenced by one of Sun Yat-sen's Three Principles of the People (i.e., the principle of welfare, minsheng zhuyi), the movement was based on traditional Confucian social ethics and promulgated ideals such as self-cultivation and correct living and discouraged the "Western" concept of individualism. Gambling, opium smoking, dancing, public displays of affection, and other activities viewed as root causes of poverty and moral degeneration were strictly forbidden.
  Scope and Contents note
  The records are chiefly made up of publications from provincial Women's Working Committees, promotional associations, and other organizations directed by Madame Chiang and sponsored by the New Life Movement. The publications cover a wide range of topics, including cooking, personal hygiene, and behavior.
  新生活運動
- Minutes of the Special Committee (Special), 1949-1950 (Reel 1)
  In April 1949 the situation in the war against the Communists turned critical, and the KMT established this emergency committee.
  中央執行委員會非常委員會會議記錄
- Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE), 1899-1953
  This collection contains confidential records created during the Second Sino-Japanese War. The material is arranged in broad subject areas. Examples of the many subjects are Central Training Squadron, Ministry of Education, Ministry of Finance, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Chinese Youth Party, central and provincial party affairs, overseas party affairs, and wartime foreign relations with Vietnam, Malaysia, India, Burma, Thailand, Korea, Singapore, the Philippines, Okinawa, Taiwan, Hong Kong, and Macau.
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 1), 1939, 1943 (Reel 1)
    特種檔案
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 2), 1905, 1939-1944 (Reels 1-4)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 3), 1905, 1939-1947 (Reels 1-3)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 4), 1905, 1935-1947 (Reels 1-7)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 5), 1905, 1934-1947 (Reels 1-4)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 6), 1905, 1932-1949 (Reels 1-10)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 7), 1905, 1940-1948 (Reel 1)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 8), 1905, 1938-1945 (Reels 1-2)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 9), 1905, 1928-1950 (Reels 1-5)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 10), 1905, 1942-1943 (Reel 1)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 11), 1905, 1940-1953 (Reels 1-10)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 12), 1942-1946 (Reel 1)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 13), 1905, 1941-1948 (Reels 1-5)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 14), 1905, 1939-1947 (Reels 1-2)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 15), 1905, 1940-1947 (Reels 1-3)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 16), 1905, 1941-1948 (Reels 1-6)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 17), 1905, 1939-1945 (Reels 1-2)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 18), 1905, 1941-1949 (Reel 1)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 19), 1905, 1941-1945 (Reel 1)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 20), 1905, 1929, 1938-1944 (Reel 1)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 21), 1905, 1941-1946 (Reels 1-2)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 22), 1905, 1942-1947 (Reel 1)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 23), 1905, 1935-1944 (Reel 1)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 24), 1905, 1939-1948 (Reels 1-5)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 25), 1905, 1941-1948 (Reels 1-4)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 26), 1905, 1940-1948 (Reels 1-4)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 27), 1905, 1938-1943 (Reel 1)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 28), 1905, 1947-1948 (Reel 1)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 29), 1905, 1928-1929 1937-1946 (Reels 1-6)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 30), 1899, 1905, 1927-1948 (Reels 1-15)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 31), 1905, 1930, 1937-1945 (Reels 1-9)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 32), 1927-1931, 1941-1951 (Reels 1-2)
  - Special Archives of the KMT Party Affairs (TE 33), 1905, 1930, 1939-1944 (Reels 1-2)
- Five Departments Archives (Wubu), 1924-1927 (Reels 1-143)
  This collection contains material concerning the five government units in operation before the Central Executive Committee was formed. The five departments were dedicated to labor unions, peasants, youth groups, women's groups, and business groups.
  五部檔案
- Central Political Council Archives (Zheng), 1898-1950
  This collection includes Central Executive Committee records, council meeting minutes, work reports, and other materials relating to Chinese national and foreign affairs. The records cover three periods: the first involves the council's establishment in Canton with Sun Yat-sen as its first chairman (1924-26), the second involves the Northern Expedition, during which Nanjing was made the capital of the Republic of China (1926-28), and the third covers the period from the July 7 Marco Polo Bridge Incident (1937), which marked the beginning of the Second Sino-Japanese War, to the end of the Chinese Civil War (1949). Other topics addressed by the documents are national security and military affairs, such as the Sino-German joint aircraft manufacturing contract and the Sino-American aviation and airmail contract.
  - Central Political Council Archives 1, 1898, 1905, 1919, 1927-1947 (Reels 1-8)
    政治檔案
  - Central Political Council Archives 2, 1905, 1926-1937 (Reels 1-8)
  - Central Political Council Archives 3, 1905, 1937-1938 (Reel 1)
  - Central Political Council Archives 4, 1905, 1920-1950 (Reels 1-11)
  - Central Political Council Archives 5 (Reels 1-9)
  - Central Political Council Archives 6, 1905, 1927-1937 (Reels 1-6)
  - Central Political Council Archives 7, 1905, 1926-1949 (Reels 1-4)
  - Central Political Council Archives 8, 1905, 1937-1949 (Reels 1-8)
  - Central Political Council Archives 9, 1928-1939 (Reels 1-2)
  - Central Political Council Archives 10, 1905, 1927-1937 (Reels 1-3)
  - Central Political Council Archives 11, 1905, 1926-1938 (Reels 1-15)
- Wu Zhihui Archive (Zhi), 1894-1952 (Reels 1-48, 48A, 49-70, 70A, 71-77, 77A, 78-125, 125A, 126, 126A, 127-138, 138A, 139-155)
  Wu Zhihui (1865-1953) has been described as a satirist, anarchist, philologist, and educator who went on to help found the Chinese Nationalist Party and the Republic of China. Wu was traditionally educated in the Chinese classics. After unsuccessful attempts to reach the top of the Qing dynasty's civil service examination system, Wu became influenced by radical thought and studied overseas in Japan, England, and France. His acquaintance with Sun Yat-sen in London eventually led him to the revolutionary movement. Wu is also known for promoting the standardization and phoneticization of the Chinese language by developing the "Symbols for Annotated Sounds" ( zhuyin fu hao) system, a phonetic system similar to Japanese kana that uses symbols to transcribe Mandarin Chinese. Widely used in Taiwan, it can be used to enter Chinese characters on cell phones and computers. Having held such official positions as minister of education, Wu was viewed as an elder statesman and close confidant of Chiang Kai-shek by many members of the Nationalist Kuomintang in his later years.
  The papers contain correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, photographs, and other materials relating to political, social, and economic conditions in China and Taiwan in the early twentieth century.
  吳稚暉檔案